So, previously we discussed to build a production-ready generator application,
there are 15 key architectural decisions or considerations we need to keep in mind.
And then we discussed about selection of the right inter legendary AI service.
We looked at the selection of the foundation model. Now over the next few lectures,
we are going to look at the third key architectural decision on responsible AI and Amazon
bedrock guardrails. So now responsible AI is an important topic and I have a full section in this course
dedicated to responsible AI. So for now, let's just focus on the Amazon bedrock guardrails
and automated reasoning. Now before we do that, let's go ahead and understand the challenges
with the foundation model and responsible AI that Amazon bedrock guardrails and automated reasoning
look to work up. So the biggest challenge with the foundation model is
halucinations, which means that foundation model can generate factually incorrect or
fabricated response. Now let's say you build an HR chatbot, which answers employee queries
based on the policy document. So there could be some scenarios where when the employee
poses a question, the chatbot driven by a large language model can answer queries that are
not retrieved from the HR policy document, but they are just fabricated and have no contextual
source. Next, we have toxicity generation of content that is offensive,
discriminatory or harmful. So there could be some scenarios where the user sends toxic content
to the large language model and it generates a response or user poses a legitimate question,
but the foundation model responds with something toxic. So there could be some scenarios where
the model leaks, private or confidential data, the PI data. So these are some of the key challenges
with foundation models and we'll see how Amazon bedrock guardrails can protect against these
challenges. Okay, now let's discuss Amazon bedrock guardrails. So Amazon bedrock guardrails implements
safeguards, customize to your application requirements and responsible AI policies.
So guardrails for Amazon bedrock provides safeguards on the top of native protection of foundation
model. So every foundation model has some native protection against the challenges that we discussed
and guardrails provides safeguards on top of those native protection. So what are the capabilities
provided as part of the Amazon bedrock? So first, we have the content filters, detect and
filter harmful text or image content in input prompts or the model responses. So let's say the user
sends harmful text, give me a plan to kill someone. So this is harmful text. So this will be
blocked by Amazon bedrock. And similarly, if this kind of response is generated by the foundation
model, it's going to be blocked by Amazon bedrock. Next is the denied topics. So block undesirable
topics in your generative AI application. Let's say you have built a banking chatbot and you want
to prohibit the chatbot from giving any investment advice. So you can define the topics where the
foundation model would not provide any response to the user queries. Next, you can do word filters,
you can block inappropriate content with a custom word filter. So let's say they are a particular
set of words which you want to block both at the input and the output level, then you can do that.
Next, we have the sensitive information filters. So when you want to redact sensitive information
to protect privacy. Now, let's say user posts a query where he provides his PI data.
All let's say, due to some reason, the model is revealing the PI data based on its training data.
So in both those scenarios, you can enable sensitive information filters that will redact the
sensitive information, including the PI data. Next, we have the contextual grounding checks,
detects and filter hallucinations in model responses based on the grounding in a source and
relevance to user query. So it's another way to reduce hallucinations. In this scenario,
what the contextual grounding checks does is once the LLM has generated a response
based on the user query, it's going to check whether the answer that has been generated
is based on the approved data source available to that foundation model. And secondly,
it's also going to check whether the answer that has been generated is relevant to the user query.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.